

Experienced web content manager pursuing an intensive full stack web development coding certificate. I am developing skills in the foundations of web development, such as JavaScript, Node.js, Handlebars, SQL, and more, while honing my skills in HTML5, CSS and responsive design.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Excellent communication skills; demonstrated ability to develop effective web content.
- Expertise in online content presentation and creating clear, concise messaging throughout the college website.
- Expert knowledge of content management systems (CMS): Sitecore and WordPress
- Proficiency in MS Office and the Adobe Creative Suite.
- HTML, CSS
- Google Analytics
- Web design
- Project management
- Quality assurance
- Information architecture
- Web/PDF accessibility
- SEO
- Writing
- Proofreading
- User Experience (UX) Design

# VANESSA PRATNICKI

**PHONE** 443.220.3820 M EMAIL

vanessa@pratnicki.net

(O) ADDRESS

**GITHUB** 

https://github.com/vpratnicki Baltimore MD, 21220





in https://www.linkedin.com/in/vanessa-pratnicki/

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development The George Washington University January 12, 2023

Bachelor of Science, Mass Communication, Advertising track **Towson University** 

Graduated in the top 10th percentile

Member of the Golden Key International Honour Society and the Lambda Pi Eta Mass Communication Honors Society

Associate of Arts, General Studies Community College of Baltimore County

Magna Cum Laude

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Community College of Baltimore County | 2005 - Present

#### **2014** present

#### **Web Content Manager**

- Administrator of Sitecore, the CMS for ccbcmd.edu.
- Test/troubleshoot implementation of new technologies on the CCBC Website.
- Create/maintain operating procedures and documentation.
- Conduct content audits to ensure content is current, relevant, adheres to our web content standards and the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) Standards for Accessible Design.
- Facilitate on-boarding of contributors into Sitecore, from designation of responsibilities to granting permissions and creating workflows.
- Determine, improve and manage the site architecture to streamline the user experience.

#### **2008 - 2014 Degree Audit Technician**

- Developed procedures and best practices for the degree audit systems to ensure that all content is consistent, clear and provides the best user experience.
- Experience using CCBC's content management system. Designated content responsibilities for the specific sections of the public facing website.
- Conducted training large training sessions to CCBC faculty, staff and students; presenting at Professional Development Day conferences and adjunct faculty conferences.

#### 2005 - 2008 Graduation Specialist

• Instrumental in the launch of two degree audit systems; programmed all course requirements using using scribe tools and coding languages.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Accessibility for Content Contributors and Designers Certificate

January 24, 2020

Mastering Web Optimization with Siteimprove Certificate December 17, 2020

National Council for Marketing and Public Relations (NCMPR) Medallion awards

- Gold Medallion: SmartREACH microsite, 2017
- Silver Medallion: Website, 2017
- Silver Medallion: Microsite, 2016
- Bronze Medallion: Website, 2015

**CCBC Enrollment and Student Services Leadership Program**May 2014